* I ngonyama
nengw' enambala *
* I ngonyama nengw' enambala *
- * I ngonyama nengw' enambala *
- [ Elephant Trumpeting ]
- [ Monkeys Chattering ]
* Night *
*And the spirit of life *
- * Calling *
- * Oh, oh, iyo *
- * Mamela *
* Uhukhosibo khokho
We ndodanaye sizwe sonke *
* Wait *
* There's no mountain too great *
- * Hear the words and have faith *
- * Oh, oh, iyo *
- * Oh, oh *
- * Have faith *
- * Hela, hey mamela *
* Hela, hey mamela
Hela, hey mamela, hela, hey mamela *
- * He lives inyou *
- * Hela, hey mamela *
- * He lives in me *
- * He watches over *
- * Hela, hey mamela *
- * Everything we see *
- * Into the water *
- * Hela, hey mamela *
- * Into the truth *
- * In your reflection *
- * Hela, hey mamela *
- * He lives inyou *
- * I ngonyama nengw' enambala *
* I ngonyama
nengw' enambala *
[ Animals Calling,
Roaring, Trumpeting ]
* *[Singing In African Language]
- * He lives inyou *
- * *[Woman Chanting
In African Language]
- * Hey, oh, yeah *
- * He lives inyou *
* Hela, hey mamela *
- * He lives in me *
- * Hela, hey mamela *
- * He watches over *
- [ Animals Cheering ]
- * Everything we see *
- * Hela, hey mamela *
- * Into the water *
- * Into the trees *
- * Hela, hey mamela *
* In your reflection *
* He lives inyou *
* I ngonyama
nengw' enambala *
- * I ngonyama nengw' enambala *
- * He lives inyou * *
Ah, Pumbaa, look
at that little guy!
A chip off the old block!
And ya gotta know
who's gonna raise him.
- His parents?
- Okay, sure. Get technical.
But who's gonna teach him
the really important stuff?
Like how to belch.
[ Belches ]
And dig for grubs.
I'm tellin' ya, buddy,
it's gonna be like old times--
You, me, and the little guy.
- [ Chuckling ] It is a girl.
- Girl.
- Girl? Oy.
- Girl? Oh.
Wow!
- [ Grunts ]
- Whoa.
- [ Laughing ]
- Where do you think
you're going in such a hurry?
[ Giggling ]
Daddy! Let go.
Well, I just want you
to be careful.
[ Childish Growling ]
Kiara, are you listening?
Accidents can happen.
- You could easily get hurt--
- " Hurt, or stepped on,
or even get lost."
[ Sighs ]
And remember--
- I want you to stay in sight
of Pride Rock at all times.
- "...at all times."
I know. "And if I see any strangers,
don't talk to them.
Come straight home."
Okay, okay. Can I go now?
- Please?
- Mm-hmm.
- Very funny.
- [ Laughs ] Mind your father, Kiara.
- [ Giggles ] Yes, Mom.
- And stay away from the outlands.
Nothing there but a bunch
of backstabbing, murderous outsiders.
Zazu's right.
You can't turn your back on them.
Really?
How come?
[ Sighs ]
Never mind. Just run along now.
- But, Dad, I--
- You'll understand someday. Go on.
- Dad!
- [ Purring ]
And stay on the path
I've marked for you.
[ Chuckles ]
Simba. Who does she remind you of, hmm?
Huh? What? Who?
She's just like you were
when you were young.
Exactly! Do you realize
the dangers we put ourselves in?
- Uh!
- You mean the dangers you put us in.
[ Chuckling ]
Hmm.
[ Laughs ]
She'll be fine.
[ Whispering ]
Hey, Timon! Pumbaa! Come here.
[ Timon ]
Good morning, mon capitaine!
I want you to keep
a close watch on Kiara.
You know she's
bound to run off.
Don't worry, Simba,
we're on her like stink on a warthog.
- Hey!
- It's a hard truth, Pumbaa.
Live with it.
Guys, I'm counting on you.
Danger could be lurking
behind every rock.
- Aha!
- Hm! Hm! Hmm.
[ Growling ]
Hey! Wait! Come back.
[ Feeble Growling ]
I just want to play.
[ Panting ]
[ Sighing ]
The mighty hunter...
has cornered her prey.
[ Childish Growling, Roaring ]
Huh?
Whoa! Cool.
The outlands.
I wonder what's out there.
[Rustling Grass]
[Twig Snapping]
- [ Screaming ]
- [ Splashing ]
Oh, don't worry, Kiara.
Uncle Pumbaa's comin'.
Oh, no! Oh! Uh, uh--
Let's see. "Gee, Simba, the good news
is we found your daughter.
The bad news is we dropped
a warthog on her.
is there a problem with that?"
- [ Gurgling ]
- Kiara? Kiara?
Pumbaa!
Let me define " baby-sitting."
[ Coughing, Choking ]
[ Spitting ]
Sorry.
Now, Princess Kiara,
as Simba's daughter,
you know better than
to go off all alone.
- You could have been hurt.
- Bu-But--
Hurt? Oh, Simba would kill us!
- You didn't slip a disk, did ya?
- Bu-Bu--
- Catch a fever? Get a hangnail?
- Aah! Timon--
- I had one once.
- Very painful.
Excruciating.
Darling, with your complexion,
you should stay out of the sun.
What? Do you wanna wrinkle?
Will somebody please
Just listen to me?
I'm sorry, I wasn't listening.
Did you say something, Princess?
I'm not just a princess, you know.
That's only half of who I am.
- Oh, uh, who's the other half?
- Oh, well, I, uh, um--
Well, while you're
figuring it out,
let's eat!
[ Snaps Fingers ]
Here we are! Grubs.
The other white meat.
- And so high in protein.
- Eww! Gross!
No? How 'bout you, big boy?
- [ Sniffing ] Ah! Love grubs.
- Not " like."
- Love!
[ Crunches, Hiccups, Spits Out ]
Oh! You always do that.
You take a bite out of every one, and
then put it back. It drives me crazy.
But you can't tell from the outside
which are the real slimy ones.
Slimy? Pumbaa,
my corpulent compadre,
it's the crunchy ones
that make the meal.
- Slimy.
- Crunchy.
- Slimy! Slimy! Slimy!
- Crunchy! Crunchy! Crunchy!
- Slimy! Slimy! Less filling.
- Crunchy! Crunchy! Tastes good.
- Less filling. Less filling.
- Tastes good. Tastes good.
[ Arguing Continues ]
[ Laughing ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Snarling ]
Who are you, pride lander?
- [ Panting ]
- [ Snarling ]
- What are you doing?
- My father says to never turn
your back on an outsider.
- You always do what Daddy says?
- No!
Bet ya do! Bet you're
Daddy's little girl. [ Scoffs ]
An outsider
doesn't need anybody.
I take care of myself.
- Really?
- [ Growling ]
- Cool!
- [Water Splashing]
[Screaming]
- [ Both Screaming ]
- [Kiara] Run!
This way!
[ Both Gasping ]
- [ Laughing ] That was a close one.
- [ Sighing ]
[ Laughing ]
Yeah.
- [ Growling ]
- [ Lions Screaming ]
Scoot!
- Whoa!
- Hey, wh-what about me?
I-I'll distract him!
Run! Whoops!
Whoop-- Oh!
[ Choking ]
- [ Screaming ]
- [ Crocodile Growling ]
- Look out!
- [ Whimpering ]
- [Screaming]
- [ Grunting ] Move it!
[ Laughing ]
Whoa!
[ Grunting ]
[ Both Gasping ]
[Roaring]
[ All Roaring ]
I did it! I did it!
[ Blows Raspberry ]
- [ Laughing ]
- Ha! [ Laughing ]
Ho, man, did you see
the size of those teeth?
They were going,
" Rr, rr, rr, rr."
[ Laughing ]
He just totally ate me up right there,
and I jumped on his head,
and I popped him so good!
We make such a good team!
And you--
You were really brave.
Yeah? You were pretty brave too.
- My name's Kovu.
- [ Giggles ] I'm Kiara.
[ Growling ]
[ Giggling ]
Tag! You're it!
Tag! You're it! You're it!
[ Laughing ]
Hello? You run, I tag.
Get it?
What's the matter?
Don't you know how to play?
Oh.
[ Growls Playfully ]
- [Laughing]
- Ah. [ Growls ]
[Thunderous Roaring]
[ Roaring ]
- Zira.
- Simba.
[Others Growling]
- Nala.
- Zira.
Timon, Pumbaa. Great!
Now that we all know each other,
- Get out of our pride lands!
- Your pride lands?
- [ Roaring ]
- [ Panicked Laughing ]
These lands belong to Scar.
I banished you
from the pride lands.
Now, you and your
young cub, get out!
Oh, haven't you met
my son, Kovu?
He was hand-chosen by Scar
to follow in his paw prints,
and become king.
- [ Growling ]
- [ Whimpering ]
Pfft! That's not a king.
That's a fuzzy maraca.
Kovu was the last born...
before you exiled us
to the outlands,
where we have little food,
less water.
You know the penalty
for returning to the pride lands.
But the child does not!
However, if you need
your pound of flesh, here.
[ Whimpering ]
Take him and get out.
We're finished here.
- [ Kiara ] Oh!
- [ Zira ] Oh, no, Simba.
We have barely begun.
[ Chuckling ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Whispering ]
Bye.
- Simba?
- [ Clears Throat ]
[ Giggles ]
- [ Sighs ]
- Kiara, what did you think
you were doing?
You could have
been killed today.
But, Daddy, I-I didn't
mean to diso--
I'm telling you this
because I love you.
- I don't want to lose you.
- I know. [ Sighs ]
If something happened to you,
I don't know what I'd do.
One day, I won't be here,
and I need you
to carry on in my place.
- You are part of the great circle of--
- "Circle of life." I know.
Exactly.
And you need to be careful.
- As future queen--
- What if I don't wanna be queen?
It's no fun.
That's like saying
you don't wanna be a lion.
It's in your blood, as I am.
- We are part of each other.
- Hmph.
Oof!.
[ Blowing ]
[ Purring ]
* As you go through life
you'll see *
* There is so much
that we *
* Don't understand *
[ Chirping ]
*And the only thing we know *
* Is things don't always go *
* The way we planned *
* But you'll see every day *
* That we'll never turn away *
* When it seems all your dreams
come undone *
- * *[Man Chanting In African]
- * We will stand by your side *
- * Filled with hope
and filled with pride *
- [ Bleating ]
* We are more than we are *
- * We are one *
- * One *
- * *[Singing In African Language]
- * We are one *
- * *[African]
* If there's so much
I must be *
* Can I still just be me *
- * The way I am *
- * *[African]
* Can I trust in my own heart *
* Or am I just one part *
- * Of some big plan *
- * *[African]
* Even those who are gone *
* Are with us as we go on *
- * Your journey has only begun *
- * *[African]
* Tears of pain
tears of joy *
* One thing nothing can destroy *
- * *[African]
- * is our pride deep inside *
- * We are one *
- * One *
* *[African]
* We are one *
- * We are one *
- * We are one, you and I *
* We are like the earth and sky *
- * One family under the sun *
- * *[African]
* All the wisdom to lead *
- *All the courage that you need *
- * *[African]
* You will find
when you see *
- * We are one *
- * One, one, one * *
* *[Chorus Fading]
As long as you live here,
- it's who you are.
- * *[Chorus Continues]
You'll understand someday.
[Bird Tweeting]
* *[African Chorus Continues]
* *[Ends]
[ Snarling ]
Kovu, Kovu, Kovu.
Scar wasn't even his father.
- He just took him in.
- [ Growling ]
Oh, hey, Vitani, where's
the little termite Kovu--
"the Chosen One" ?
[ Laughing ]
Nuka, where's Kovu?
Did you leave him out there
on his own again?
Hey! It's every lion
for himself out here.
- [ Insects Buzzing ]
- That little termite's
gotta learn to be on his own.
Mother's gonna be mad.
She told you to watch him.
Oh, who cares?
I shoulda been the Chosen One.
I'm the oldest.
I'm the strongest. I'm the smartest--
Oh, these termites!
[ Yelping ]
I could be a leader,
if she'd just give me a chance.
[ Scoffs ] Yeah, right.
Why don't you tell that to her?
Yeah? Don't think I won't.
Oh, yeah?
[ Chuckles ] Here's your chance.
- What? Oh! Mother. Mother! Hi!
- [Growling]
[ Giggling ] Mother, I caught
some field mice for your dinner.
I left 'em by the, um--
by the-- Okay.
[Vitani]
Hey, Kovu,
wanna fight?
[ Growling ]
- You were supposed to be watching him.
- [ Gasps ]
I-It's not his fault.
I went off on my own.
- What were you doing?
- [ Whimpering ] Nothing.
- Who has made us outsiders?
- Simba.
- Who killed Scar?
- Simba!
What have I told you
about them?
I'm sorry, Mother. Oh, I--
She didn't seem so bad.
Oh, I-I-I-I--
I thought we could be--
Friends? You thought
you'd get to the daughter,
and Simba would welcome you
with open arms?
What an idea.
What an idea!
- You brilliant child.
I'm so proud of you.
- [ Gasps ]
- You have the same conniving mind...
- [ Whimpering ]
that made Scar so... powerful.
- Ugh. Yuch.
- [ Roaring ]
[ Weak Laughter ]
[ Groaning ]
Bah. "Chosen One."
[ Grunts ]
I now see the path...
to our glorious return...
to power!
- But I don't want--
- Hush!
Hush, my little one.
You must be exhausted.
* Sleep, my little Kovu *
* Let your dreams take wing *
* One day when you're
big and strong *
* You will be a king *
- Good night.
- Good night, my little prince.
Tomorrow your training
intensifies.
* I've been exiled, persecuted *
* Left alone with no defense *
* When I think of what
that brute did *
* I get a little tense *
* But I dream a dream
so pretty *
* That I don't feel
so depressed *
* 'Cause it soothes
my inner kitty *
* And it helps me
get some rest *
* The sound of Simba's
dying gasp *
[ Mock Screaming ]
* His daughter squealing
in my grasp *
* His lioness's
mournful cry *
* That's my lullaby *
* Now, the past
I've tried forgetting *
* And my foes
I could forgive *
* Trouble is
I know it's petty *
* But I hate
to let them live *
*So you found
yourself somebody *
* Who'll chase Simba
up a tree *
* Oh, the battle
may be bloody *
- * But that kind of works for me *
- [ Screaming ]
- * The melody of angry growls *
- [ Growling ]
- * A counterpoint of painful howls *
- [ Howling ]
* A symphony of death
Oh, my *
* That's my lullaby *
* Scar is gone
But Zira's still around *
* To love this little lad *
[ Slurps ]
* Till he learns to be
a killer *
* With a lust
for being bad *
* Sleep, ya little termite
I mean, precious little thing *
* One day when you're
big and strong *
* You will be a king *
* *[Pounding Drums]
* The pounding of
the drums of war *
* The thrill of
Kovu's mighty roar *
- * The joy of vengeance *
- Testify!
* I can hear the cheering *
- * Kovu-- what a guy *
* Payback time is nearing *
* And then our flag will fly *
* Against a blood-red sky *
* That's my lullaby *
[ Cackling ]
Oh, Mufasa.
Every day Kiara grows more beautiful,
into a queen that will someday
make us all very proud.
But this cub, Kovu,
grows stronger,
and Zira fills
his heart with hate.
I'm very worried, Mufasa.
Things are not
going well, no.
Hmm? You have a plan?
What?
Kovu? Kiara?
Together?
This is the plan?
Are you crazy?
This will never work.
Oh, Mufasa, you been up there too long.
Your head is in the clouds.
- [Wind Gusting]
- Okay, okay, okay.
Okay, all right, okay!
I don't think this is
going to work, but I trust you.
I just hope you know
what you are doing!
You are ready!
[ Chuckling ]
Mm, nice.
Very... nice.
[ Chuckling ]
- You have the same blackness
in your soul that Scar had.
- [ Growling ]
What is your destiny?
I will avenge Scar.
- Take his place in the pride lands.
- Yes! What have I taught you?
Simba is the enemy.
And what must you do?
I must kill him.
[ Snarling ]
[ Chattering ]
- [Female #1 Murmuring]
This is Kiara's first hunt.
- [ Sighing ]
- [Female #2] There she is!
- Kiara.
- Aha!
- [Female #1 ] You can do it.
[Female #2]
It's your day.
[Excited Chattering, Indistinct]
My, how you've grown.
Hmm. You'll do just fine.
Daddy? You have to promise
to let me do this on my own.
Promise?
All right. I promise.
Make sure she doesn't get hurt.
- Ah! Mm.
- * * [ Humming ]
- [Twig Snaps]
- [ Gasps ]
Eww. This place is even creepier
since the hyenas ran off.
Oh, sheesh.
- [ Scoffs ] I'm not scared, okay?
- [Hissing Sound]
[ Whimpers ]
I just don't know why
we have to be here, that's all.
If Kovu is so special,
why does he need us?
- [Hissing]
- I never even had a chance!
[ Screaming, Whimpering ]
That's it!
Well, come on.
Kiara has started her hunt.
We have to move quickly.
[ Whimpering ]
Ow, fire!
[ Laughs Hysterically ]
Ah!
Hut! Hut!
[ Grass Rustling ]
Tango Charlie Alpha.
What's your position?
Uh... upright? Head turned
slightly to the left, tail erect.
Why do I bother?
Aha!
- Ooh.
- [ Stone Rattles ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Both Screaming ]
[ Timon ] This must be where
the deer and the antelope play.
- [ Screaming ]
- [ Panting ]
- [ Laughing Uneasily ]
- Timon, what are you doing here?
Uh, shopping!
We thought a nice pelt for the den,
some throw pillows,
a little potpourri--
My father sent you. After he promised
to let me do this on my own, he lied.
No. He just doesn't
want you to get hurt.
I should have known
he'd never give me a real chance.
I'll do this on my own!
Away from the pride lands.
Hey! Wait!
Come back! Ah!
- [ Pumbaa ] Look behind you!
- [ Timon ] Kiara! Come back!
Oh-ho! She's gone again.
Somebody's gotta get
a beeper for this kid.
[ Panting ]
[ Nuka ]
Let's light fires!
[ Chuckling ]
[ Yelling, Laughing ]
* Roasty-toasty princess
roasty-toasty princess * *
Hey, is it hot in here,
or is that just me?
Fire!
[ Screaming ]
- [ Laughing ]
- Come on.
Wha--
[ Gasps ]
The plan is in motion. Go!
Don't worry, Simba.
She'll be fine!
What could happen?
[ Gasps ]
No! No! Kiara!
- [ Gasps ]
- Zazu! Fly ahead! Find her!
- [ Growling ]
- [ Frightened Neighing ]
[ Panting ]
Oh!
[ Screams ]
[ Coughing ]
No!
[ Panting, Grunting ]
[ Grunting, Sighing ]
- [ Deep Growling ]
- [ Moaning ]
[ Growling ]
[ Sighing ]
[ Snarling ]
[ Kovu Grunting ]
[ Gasps ]
I must tell Simba!
[ Coughing, Gasping ]
- Where am I ?
- You're safe. I n the pride lands.
The pride lands? No!
Why'd you bring me here?
Who do you think you are?
[ Gasps ] I think I'm the one
that just saved your life.
Look, I had everything
under control.
- Not from where I'm standing.
- Then move downwind.
[ Growls ]
[ Grunts, Sighs, Growls ]
What are you doing?
Kovu?
Kiara!
[Snarling]
Kiara, you're all right.
Father, how could you
breakyour promise?
It's a good thing I did.
I almost lost you.
No more hunts for you.
Not ever.
But I was doing just fine!
Even before Kovu--
- Kovu?
- [Both Snarling]
- Simba!
- [ Growling ]
Hey! You!
How dare you save
the king's daughter?
You saved her? Why?
- I humbly ask to join your pride.
- No!
You were banished
with the other outsiders.
I have left the outsiders.
I am a rogue.
Judge me now for who I am.
[Sighing]
Or am I to be blamed
for a crime I didn't commit?
[ Growling ]
Simba, you owe him
your daughter's life.
Hmm, yes, sire.
Clearly we are in his debt.
And royal protocol demands
that all debts be paid.
Though in this case,
you might want to make an exception.
Hmm.
My father's law will prevail.
For now, I reserve judgment.
We'll see who you really are.
Hmm.
Hmph! Riffraff.
[ Growling ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Growls ]
Hey, uh, thanks
for saving me today.
[ Laughs ] What kind of hunter
are you, anyway... Princess?
You almost got yourself
killed out there.
- What?
- You wouldn't last
three days on your own.
Oh, and I suppose you
could teach me?
[ Laughs ]
Oh. Yeah.
- [Simba] Kiara!
- Coming.
All right! Impress me.
We start at dawn.
[ Chuckling ]
I look forward to it.
[ Sputtering ]
Did you see that?
- He let her go! If that were me, I--
- Hush.
The fire rescue
worked perfectly,
and Simba fell for it.
Now, the closer Kovu
gets to the daughter,
the closer he gets
to Simba!
And once he has Simba alone--
[ Snarls ]
[ Panting, Grunting ]
[Male Voice, Echoing]
Simba! Simba!
- Help me!
- Father!
[Evil Laughing, Echoing]
No! Dad!
Just a little farther.
- [Scar] Gotcha!
- [ Screams ]
- Trust me.
- Simba!
No!
- Scar.
- [ Laughing ]
- Kovu?
- Hyah!
No!
[ Panting, Gasping ]
[ Growling ]
Good morning.
[ Laughing ]
I'm ready for my first lesson.
Surprised ya, huh?
Hey, come on.
[ Laughing ] Let's go.
[ Growling ]
- [Grass Rustling]
- [Panting] Ow.
Ow! Ow.
[ Sighing ]
Three, two, one.
Gotcha!
You could hear me, huh?
Only a lot.
You're still breathing too hard.
Relax. Feel the earth
under your paws,
so it doesn't shift
and make noise.
- [ Sighs ]
- [ Birds Calling ]
Shh! Watch the master and learn.
- [ Roaring ]
- [ Screaming ]
Don't eat me, please.
I-I-I never really met your tyrant--
I mean, uh, Scar. Scar.
Oh, heck of a guy.
A little moody, but--
Timon, what are
you doing here?
Kiara! Thank goodness!
Oh! Hey, for once,
we're not followin' ya.
This just happens to be
the best smorgasbord in the pride lands.
Bugs everywhere!
But, you don't call
for a reservation, and-- Yeesh!
Get outta here, ya scavengers.
Go on! Shoo!
- Shoo! Ow!
- [ Swallowing ]
[ Crying ]
Oh-ho-ho. Oh!
[ Screaming Wildly ]
[ Laughing, Screaming Wildly ]
- [ Laughing ]
- Oh, Timon! I'm gettin' tired.
I gotta lose some pounds.
Shoo! Go on!
Shoo! Shoo!
- [ Laughing ]
- Hey, maybe he could help.
- Do you think?
- Shoo!
Oh, yeah, there's an idea.
Right. Let the vicious outsider--
Hey! Wait!
I have an idea.
- What if he helps?
- What?
You want to lend
a voice? Hah?
Grr. Gr--
Roar! Work with me!
- Uh, huh?
- Like this. [ Roaring ]
- [ Roaring Continues ]
- [ Birds Chirping ]
Whoo-hoo! Come on.
Do it again. Do it again.
- [ Louder Roaring ]
- [ Timon ] Yee-ha! [ Blows Raspberry ]
Why are we doing this?
What's the point of this training?
[ Laughing ]
Training? This is just for fun!
- Fun?
- [ Laughing ]
Yeesh, kid.
Ya gotta get out more often.
Fun! Yee-ha!
[ Laughing ]
Woo-hoo! Yee-ha!
- Yee-ha!
- [ Laughing ]
- [ Birds Twittering ]
[ Timon ]
Whoa-oh-oh! [ Laughs ]
- Yee-ha!
- [Kiara] Yee- ha!
[ All Laughing ]
[ Screaming ]
- Uh-oh.
- [ Blowing Raspberry ]
- [ Bellowing ]
- Wow!
[ All ]
Yee-ha!
- Whoa!
[ Timon ]
Hey, rhino!
[ Laughing ]
- What a blast!
- Oh. Sorry.
- [ Kovu, Kiara Laughing ]
- Aha! You're okay, kid.
- Hey!
- You're okay.
- Kid.
- Excuse me. Pardon me. Pardon me.
- [ Groaning ]
- That's it. That's it. That's it. Ooh--
- A-Ahem. [ Laughing ]
- [ Laughing ]
- Um-- S-Sorry. Uh--
- [ Stammering ]
- [ Timon ] Hey, are you two
coming or what?
- [ Kiara Giggling ]
[Kovu] Did you see that?
Did you see that? Watch.
- Oh, wow. Look at that.
It's really pretty.
- What? Oh, yeah.
You're right.
Oh, look!
There's one that looks like
a baby rabbit. See the fluffy tail?
Yeah. Hey!
There's one that looks like two lions
killing each other for a scrap of meat.
[Laughs]
Hey, I've never done this before.
Really? My father and I
used to do this all the time.
He says all the great kings
of the past are up there. [ Chuckles ]
[ Whispering ]
Do ya think Scar's up there?
He wasn't my father,
but he was still... part of me.
My father said
there was a--
a darkness in Scar
that he couldn't escape.
Maybe there's
a darkness in me too.
[ Purring ]
Father, I am lost.
Kovu is one of them.
Scar's heir.
- How can I accept him?
- Simba?
I was seeking counsel
from the great kings.
- Did they help?
- [ Sighs ]
[ Simba ]
Silent as stars. My father would never--
Oh, my Simba.
You want so much
to walk the path expected of you.
- Perhaps Kovu does not.
- What? How do you know--
[ Laughing ] I can see them down there
Just as easily as you can.
Get to know him and see.
- [ Clears Throat ]
- What's wrong?
Nothing.
- Kovu--
- It's just that my whole life
I've been trained to--
[ Sighs ]
Nothing.
- I gotta go.
- Kovu, wait.
[ Rafiki ]
And where are you going?
N-Nowhere.
Ha! That's what you think!
[ Laughs ]
- Who was that?
- Uh, friend of the family.
Mm. Mm- hmm.
Mm- hmm. Mm- hmm. Come on!
You follow old Rafiki.
He knows the way. [ Snickering ]
- The way to where?
- [ Laughing ] You follow! You'll see!
Hurry now!
[ Laughing ]
Kovu, come on!
Where's he taking us?
A place in your heart
called Upendi.
* *[African Instrument]
[Laughing]
* There's a place
where the crazy moon *
* Makes the monkeys sing
and the baboons woon *
* And the sultry scent
of the lotus bloom *
- * Will carry you away *
- [ Sneezing ]
* While the hippos swing
from the jungle vines *
* And the rhino rumba
in a conga line *
*All the pink flamingoes
are intertwined *
*As the stars come out to play
Uhh *
* In Upendi where
the passion fruit grows sweet *
* And it's so divine
that you lose your mind *
* As it sweeps you
off your feet *
* I n Upendi
without a worry or a care *
* it just takes two
to make it true *
- * Your heart will lead you there *
- [Kiara Laughing]
- Where is it?
- * In Upendi *
- No place you don't take with you.
[ Laughing ]
* Better watch your step
'cause the path is steep *
* Better hold your breath
'cause the water's deep *
* It's a long way down
over Lover's Leap *
* But falling's half the fun *
- * In Upendi *
- [ Laughing ]
* Where the passion fruit
grows sweet *
*And it's so divine
that you'll lose your mind *
*As it sweeps you
off your feet *
* I n Upendi
without a worry or a care *
* It just takes two
to make it true *
* Your heart will
take you there *
* You can beat the bush
like there's no tomorrow *
* From Tanganyika
to Kilimanjaro *
* But you'll find Upendi
wherever you are *
- * Oh, underneath the sun *
- Upendi. It means love, doesn't it?
* Welcome to Upendi *
- * In Upendi *
- * Where the passion fruit grows sweet *
* Oh, it's so divine
that you'll lose your mind *
*As it sweeps you
off your feet *
* In Upendi
without a worry or a care *
* It just takes two
to make it true *
- * Your heart *
- * Heart *
* Will take you there *
* Upendi *
- * Down in Upendi, way down in Upendi *
- [ Kiara Laughs, Sings Along ]
* Down in Upendi, way down in Upendi *
- * I n Upendi, in Upendi *
- * Down in Upendi, way down in Upendi *
[Laughs]
- [Kiara] * In Upendi *
- [Kovu Chuckles]
[ Kovu ]
* I n Upendi, in Upendi * *
[ Both Laughing ]
- Good night.
[ Sighs ]
It's kinda cold tonight, huh?
Come on in.
[ Panting ]
Get him!
What are you waiting for?
Kovu, get him!
[ Scoffs ]
[ Snarling ]
-You're sure?
-Affirmative. I saw it with my own eyes.
No. Kovu cannot betray us.
Okay, I have
to tell her today.
Oh, where do I start?
" Kiara, Zira had a plot,
and I was part of it,
but I don't wanna be because--
It's because I love you."
[ Sighs ]
Aw, she'll never believe me.
But I gotta try.
Kiara, I--
I need to talk to you.
- Kiara, I don't want you
talking with him.
- [ Gasps ]
I want to talk with him.
Scar couldn't
let go of his hate,
and in the end,
it destroyed him.
I've never heard
the story of Scar that way.
He truly was a killer.
[Simba]
Fire is a killer.
Sometimes what's left behind can grow
better than the generation before...
if given the chance.
- [Low Chuckle]
- [ Gasps ]
[ Snarls ]
[ Gasps ]
Oh, no. No!
- [ Chuckling ] Why, Simba.
- Zira.
What are you doing out here--
and so alone?
[ Growling ]
[ Growling, Chuckling ]
Well done, Kovu.
Just like we always planned.
- You!
- No! I didn't have
anything to do with this!
- Attack!
- [ Snarling ]
- No!
- [ Snarling, Groaning ]
[ Growling, Groaning ]
[ All Growling, Snarling ]
[ Groans ]
Yes! We've got him!
- [ Snarling ]
- [Zira] Remember your training!
As a unit!
[ Snarling, Growling ]
- Simba!
- Get him, Kovu! Get him!
Do it now!
I'll do it for you, Mother!
[ Cackling ]
Oof!.
Mother, are you watching?
I'm doin' it for you,
and I'm doin' it for me. [ Snickers ]
- Uh!
- [ Snarls ]
- [ Grunts ]
- This is my moment of glory!
- What? No!
- No!
- Ow!
- [ Grunts ]
- Uh--
[ Logs Crashing ]
- [ Grunts ]
- [ Snarls ]
- [ Coughing ]
- Nuka!
- I'm sorry, Mother.
I tried.
- Shh!
- [ Whimpers ]
- [ Sighing ]
- Nuka.
Father?
Father! Zazu, get help!
Oh, yes! Help!
At once! Of course!
- [ Grunts ]
- Father!
Simba, talk to me!
What happened?
[ Coughing ]
Kovu-- Ambush. [ Groans ]
No.
It's all right, buddy.
We're here for you.
Scar, watch over
my poor Nuka.
- You!
- [ Groans ]
What have you done?
I didn't--
I-I didn't mean to.
It wasn't my fault. I--
I did nothing.
Exactly! And in doing so,
you betrayed your pride--
Betrayed Scar!
I want nothing more
to do with him!
You cannot escape it.
Nuka is dead because of you!
- No.
- You've killed your own brother!
- No!
- [ Lions Snarling ]
Let him go.
Simba has hurt me for the last time.
Now he has corrupted Kovu!
Listen to me.
Simba is injured and weak.
Now is the time to attack!
We will take
his entire kingdom...
- by force!
- [ All Snarling ]
[ Cackling ]
- Daddy, it can't be true.
- [Male] It's Kovu!
- Hey!
- It's Kovu!
- [ Animals Murmuring ]
- Kovu!
[ Snarling ]
[ Animals Whispering ]
Oh! Why, I oughta--
Let me at 'im! Let me at 'im!
- Here. Hold me back.
- Okay.
- Let me at 'im! Let me at 'im!
- I think you're missing
the basic point here.
- Oh.
[ Whispering ]
What's he doing?
Look at that scar
on his face.
[ Animals Continue Murmuring ]
- Why have you come back?
- Simba, I had nothing to do with--
- You don't belong here.
- Please. I ask your forgiveness.
Daddy, please!
Listen to him!
Silence! When you first
came here you asked for judgment.
- And I pass it now!
- [Animals Jeering]
- Exile!
- No!
[Rhythmic Pounding]
[ Trumpeting ]
[ Screeching ]
- No!
- [ Snarling ]
- Kovu!
- [Elephant Trumpets]
[ Growling ]
* Deception *
* Disgrace *
* Evil as plain
as the scar on his face *
- * Deception *
- * An outrage *
- * Disgrace *
- * For shame *
* He asked for trouble
the moment he came *
- * Deception *
- * An outrage *
- * Disgrace *
- * For shame *
* Evil as plain
as the scar on his face *
- * Deception *
- *An outrage *
- * Disgrace *
- * For shame *
* He asked for trouble
the moment he came *
*See ya later, agitator *
* Born in grief
Raised in hate *
* Helpless to defy his fate *
* Let him run, let him live *
* But do not forget
what we never forgive *
* He is not *
* One of us *
* He has never been
one of us *
* He is not one of us *
* Not our kind *
*Someone once lied to us *
* Now we're not so blind *
* For we knew he would do
what he's done *
*And we know that
he'll never be *
* One of us *
[Kiara]
* He is not one of us *
* Deception *
* Disgrace *
* Mmm- mm, deception *
* Deception * *
Ooh.
- Father, please reconsider.
- You will not go anywhere...
without an escort from now on.
- No! That's not--
- He used you to get to me.
- No! He loves me-- for me!
- Because you are my daughter.
You will not leave Pride Rock.
You will stay where I can
keep an eye on you-- away from him.
- You don't know him!
- I know he's following
in Scar's paw prints.
- And I must follow in my father's.
- You will never be Mufasa.
[ Sobs ]
Kovu?
[ Sighs ]
[ Sobbing ]
[Kiara]
* In a perfect world *
* One we've never known *
* We would never need *
* To face the world alone *
* They can have the world *
* We'll create our own *
* I may not be brave
or strong or smart *
* But somewhere
in my secret heart *
* I know *
* Love will find a way *
*Anywhere I go *
* I'm home *
* If you are there beside me *
* Like dark turning into day *
*Somehow we'll come through *
* Now that I've found you *
* Love will find a way *
[Kovu]
* I was so afraid *
* Now I realize *
* Love is never wrong *
*And so it never dies *
* There's a perfect world *
*Shining in your eyes *
[Both]
*And if only they could feel it too *
* The happiness
I feel with you *
* They'd know *
* Love will find a way *
*Anywhere we go we're home *
* If we are there together *
* Like dark turning into day *
*Somehow we'll come through *
* Now that I've found you *
* Love will find a way *
* I know *
* Love will find *
*A way * *
[ Gasps ]
Hey!
[ Laughing ]
[ Both Laughing ]
Uh, hey.
Hey, look.
We are one.
What?
Let's get out of here.
We'll run away together!
And start a pride
all our own.
[ Laughs ]
Kovu,
we have to go back.
You're kidding.
But we're finally together.
Our place is with our pride.
If we run away,
they'll be divided forever.
[ Growling ]
[Thunder Rumbling]
[Timon]
I can't believe we lost her again.
This is the 8,000th time!
- [ Groans ]
- I thought you were gonna watch her!
- Me? You were gonna watch her!
- No, you were gonna watch her!
- You were gonna watch her!
- Oh, watch this!
- [ Groans ] Take that,
you creepy warthog!
- [Timon] Say it! Say it!
- [Pumbaa Yelling]
- What are you doing?
- Uh--
Good question.
Uh, let me ask you one.
- " Hippo-thetically."
- Very hypothetical.
- There's this guy--
- But he's not a lion.
No! No,
he's not a lion.
Geez! Definitely not a lion!
And uh, uh,
his daughter, uh,
say... vanished.
-Kiara's gone?
-Sire, the outsiders are on the attack!
Heading this way!
It's war!
Zazu, find Kiara. We'll assemble
the lionesses. Move. Now!
[Thunder Rolling]
[ Squawking ]
[ Growling ]
[ Snarls ]
[ Squawking ]
[ Both ]
* Na-na-na na-na-na * *
It's over, Simba.
I have dreamed
of nothing else for years.
Oy, does she need a hobby.
Last chance, Zira. Go home.
I am home.
[ Snarls ]
- [Thunderclap]
- Attack!
[ Snarling, Growling ]
[ Roaring ]
- [ Snarling, Growling ]
- Go for the eyes!
- [ Roaring ]
- Break his jaw! Hit him low!
Get them!
Do what you must!
What do we do?
There's only one thing
we can do, Pumbaa.
"When the going gets tough,
the tough get going." That's our motto!
I thought our motto was,
"Hakuna matata. "
Pumbaa, stop living in the past.
- We need a new motto. Yee-ha!
- Whoo!
- [ Roaring ]
- [ Both Screaming ]
Like I said,
let's get going!
- Where's your pretty daughter, Nala?
- Vitani!
[ Snarling ]
[ Whimpering ]
Look out! Ow!
[ Snarling, Growling ]
- [ Pumbaa Whimpering ]
- [ Teeth Chattering ] Huh?
- [ Whimpering ]
- [ Chuckles ]
- [ Clicking ]
- Don't anybody move!
This thing's loaded.
I'll let you have it!
- [ All Screaming ]
- [Timon] Yeah! Yeah!
[ Laughing ]
- Ha! Talk about your winds of war!
- [ Chuckling ]
- [ Snarling, Growling ]
- Simba!
You're mine!
[Snarling, Growling]
- [ Snarling ]
- [ Roaring ]
- Kiara?
- Kovu!
- Move.
- Stand aside.
Daddy, this has to stop.
You're even weaker than I thought.
Get out of the way!
You'll never hurt Kiara-- or Simba.
Not while I'm here.
- Hah!
- Stay out of this.
A wise king once told me,
"We are one."
I didn't understand him then.
Now I do.
- But they--
- "Them" ? Us! Look at them.
They are us.
What differences do you see?
Vitani-- now!
No, Mother.
Kiara's right.
Enough.
If you will not fight,
then you will die as well.
What? Where are--
Where are you going?
Get back here!
Let it go, Zira.
It's time to put the past behind us.
I'll never let it go!
[Cracking, Crashing]
This is for you, Scar!
[ Roaring ]
- [ Kiara Whimpers ]
- Kiara!
Kiara!
- [ Yelling ]
[Kiara Whimpers]
- [ Gasping ]
- Hold on, Kiara!
Simba! Simba, the river!
[ Gasps, Grunts ]
Zira, give me your paw.
Zira, come on!
- I'll help you.
- Ohh!
[ Screaming ]
[ Sighs ]
- [ Sighs ]
- [Simba] Kiara?
Daddy!
I tried.
Kiara!
- [ Laughing ]
- Wow! That was really brave!
Yee-ha!
- Kovu.
- Oh, Kiara.
Kovu?
I was wrong.
You belong here.
Let's go home.
All of us.
[ Rattling ]
- I love moments like this!
- Yeah.
[ Both ]
Love! Not " like,"
love!
[ Both Sobbing ]
[ Roaring ]
[ All Roaring ]
- [ Chattering, Laughing ]
- [ Trumpets ]
[Voice Of Mufasa]
Well done, my son.
[Voice of Mufasa]
We are one.
* *
* Ooh, ooh *
* In a perfect world *
* One we've never known *
* We would never need *
* To face the world alone *
* They can have their world *
* We'll create our own *
* I may not be brave
or strong or smart *
* But somewhere
in my secret heart *
* I know *
* Love will find a way *
*Anywhere I go
I'm home *
* If you are there
beside of me *
* Like dark *
* Turning into day *
*Somehow we'll come through *
* Now that I found you *
* Love will find a way *
* I was so afraid *
* Now I realize *
* Love is never wrong *
*And so, it never dies *
* Mmm, there's a perfect world *
*Shining in your eyes *
*And if only they
could feel it too *
* The happiness
I feel with you *
* They'd know *
* Love will find a way *
*Anywhere we go
we're home *
* If we are there together *
* Like dark *
* Turning into day *
*Somehow we'll come through *
* Now that I found you *
* Love will find a way *
* Oh, yeah *
* *[Vocalizing]
* *
* I know *
- * Love will find a way *
- * Oh, yes, it will *
- *Anywhere we go I'm home *
- * I'm home, right there *
* If we are there together *
* Like dark *
* Turning into day *
*Somehow we'll come through *
* Now that I found you *
* Love will find a way *
* I know love will find *
*A way *
* I know *
* Love will find *
*A *
* Way * *